Guide to the Allen Forte Papers
Yale University Music Library
Allen Forte Papers
1955-2014
MSS 135
Yale University Music Library
7.5
(15 containers)
The Allen Forte Collection includes theoretical analyses (published and unpublished); materials related to courses that Forte taught; general theory materials; drafts of articles and lectures; and a small number of photos, personal documents, books and scores.
Forte, Allen, 1926-2014
Arrangement
The Allen Forte Papers are comprised of five series: I. Analyses; II. Correspondence; III. Teaching and general theory materials; IV. Manuscript drafts, writings, and lectures; and V. Photos, personal documents, books and scores.
Biographical / Historical
Allen Forte (1926-2014) was the Battell Professor Emeritus of the Theory of Music at Yale University. He was a specialist in 20th-century atonal music, musical analysis using Schenkerian methods, and the American popular ballad. He is the author of over one hundred books and articles, and advised seventy-two Ph.D. dissertations. Allen Forte received his B.A. and M.A. from Columbia University, and taught at Columbia University Teachers College, Manhattan School of Music, and Mannes College of Music before joining the faculty of Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The Allen Forte Collection includes theoretical analyses (published and unpublished) of the works of a wide variety of composers; a selection of Forte's correspondence, which includes letters to and from Ernst Oster, Gertrud Schoenberg, and other notable music theorists; materials related to some of the courses Forte taught; general theory materials; drafts of some of Forte's published and unpublished articles and lectures; and a selection of photos, personal documents, books and scores.
Related Materials
Researchers may wish to consult the Allen Forte Electronic Archive, and the Allen and Madeleine Forte Memorial Collection, both housed at the University of North Texas Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Allen and Madeleine Forte.
Music theory; Schenkerian analysis; Forte, Allen, 1926-2014
- Analyses
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of analytical notes and graphs, organized by composer. In most cases the analyses are of a single movement or section. Many are detailed, and some that were used for publication have copies of formatted examples. A few are very rudimentary and incomplete. Some composers are represented by a single work; others by 10 or more. Composers with a large number of analyzed works include J.S. Bach, Beethoven, Debussy, Schoenberg, Schubert, Stravinsky, and Webern. A small amount of analytical materials from conferences, with annotations by Forte, are included. In a few instances correspondence about the analysis of a particular work is included.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by composer, and then by opus number or date of composition, if possible. Dates shown after the composer's name or title of the work indicate the date of Forte's analysis, if it is indicated.
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Analyses of "Three Theatrical Songs" (As Long as It Isn't Love; Penelope's Night Song; Now You See It) and "The Widow's Lament in Springtime". Also includes material and correspondence regarding a talk given at A Symposium in Honor of Milton Babbitt (1998) and article publication, both entitled 'Milton Babbitt's "Three Theatrical Songs" in Perspective".
  - Bach, J.S. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cantata No. 21, BWV 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Soprano aria.
    - Chorales, Nos. 5 (BWV 267), 14 (BWV 384), 271 (BWV 315) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Inventio 4, D minor, BWV 775, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Include analyses dated 1969 and 1976.
    - Inventio 5, Eb major, BWV 776, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Also includes analysis by M. MacLean.
    - Inventio 8, F major, BWV 779, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sinfonia No. 15, B minor, BWV 801, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - English Suite No. 4, F major, BWV 809, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Menuet II
    - French Suite No. 1, D minor, BWV 812, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Sarabande
    - French Suite No. 2, C minor, BWV 813, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Courante, Sarabande, Menuet
    - French Suite No. 3, B minor, BWV 814 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Menuet
    - French Suite No. 4, Eb major, BWV 815, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Prelude No. 2, C minor, WTC I, BWV 847 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Prelude No. 23, B major, WTC I, BWV 868 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Prelude and Fugue No. 7, Eb major, WTC II, BWV 876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Prelude No 12, F minor, WTC II, BWV 881, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Fugue Subjects from WTC I and II, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes note from Lee Rothfarb.
    - Little Prelude, C major, BWV 924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Include correspondence from Ernst Oster about the "Small Preludes".
    - Little Prelude, C minor, BWV 934, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Short Prelude, A minor, BWV 942, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sonata, Violin, G minor, BWV 1001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Presto
    - Partita, Violin, B Minor, BWV 1002, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Bourrée, Double, Sarabande
    - Cello Suite, G major, BWV 1007, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Menuets I and II
    - Cello Suite, D minor, BWV 1008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Gigue
    - Cello Suite, Eb major, BWV 1010, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Prelude
    - Orchestral Suite No. 3, D major, BWV 1068, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Air
  - Bach, C.P.E. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Kurze und Leichte Klavierstücke, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Nos. 1, 2, 6, 15a,19, 22
    - Essay Sonata I (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Minuetto
  - Bartók, Béla (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Duke Bluebeard's Castle (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fourteen Bagatelles, Op. 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      No 1 (1977); No. 2 (1977); No. 8 (1977); No. 9 (1988)
    - First String Quartet, Introduction to Movement III, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fourth String Quartet, Movement IV, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes analyses by Randy Wheaton and Richard Hermann
    - Piano Sonata II (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Suite for Piano, Op. 14, Movement IV, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No. 1, F minor, Op. 2 /1, Menuetto, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No. 4, Eb major, Op 7, Movement II and III (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No. 5, C minor, Op. 10/1, Movement III, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No. 8, C minor, Op. 13, Movement III, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No. 9, E major, Op. 14/1; Movement I and II, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Include Oster sketches for Schachter talk.
    - String Quartet No. 1, F major, Op. 18/1, Movement 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Inclues list and copies of known sketches.
    - Violin Sonata No. 5, F major, Op. 24/1, Movement I (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes letter from Ernst Oster.
    - Piano Sonata No. 15, D major, Op. 28, Movement III (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes analysis by Jeanne Swack.
    - Bagatelle, D Major, Op. 33/6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 2, D major, Op. 36, Movement II, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 6, F Major, Op. 68, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes letter and sketches from Ernst Oster.
    - Symphony No. 7, A major, Op. 92, Introduction, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes analyses by Peter Marshall and Darlene Berkovitz.
    - Bagatelle, C major, Op. 119/8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bagatelle, Eb Major, Op. 126/6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes analysis by J. Schmalfeldt.
    - String Quartet, Bb Major, Op. 130, Movement IV, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Berg, Alban (Box 2)
    - Four Lieder, Op. 2 No. 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Four Lieder, Op. 2 No. 4 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Includes Abstract for "Berg's First Atonal Composition".
    - String Quartet, Op. 3, Movement I and II (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Four Pieces for Clarinet and Piano, Op. 5, No. 1 and 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Altenberg Lieder, Op. 4, No. 2 and 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Three Pieces for Orchestra, Op. 6, No. 1 and 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Includes materials from Mark DeVoto presentation, AMS 1976.
    - Lyric Suite for String Quartet, Movement III (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Wozzeck, Motives (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Wozzeck, Theoretical Aspects (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Wozzeck, Act I, Scenes 1, 2, 3, 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Wozzeck, Act II, Scenes 1-5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Wozzeck, Act III, Scenes 1, 3, 4, 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Analyses of Berg pieces (not by A.F.) from various conference presentations (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Phillips - Op. 3; Rockmaker - Op. 3; McLean - Op. 6
  - Berlioz, Hector (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Analysis of "La Damnation de Faust", Sc. XVI.
  - Boulez, Pierre (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Analysis of "Improvisation sur mallarmé".
  - Brahms, Johannes (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Variations of a Theme by Schumann, Op. 9, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ein Deutsches Requiem, Op. 43, Movement III (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Four Songs, "Die Mainacht", Op. 43/2, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet, C minor, Op. 51, Movement I (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Alto Rhapsody, Op. 53, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - First Symphony, Op. 68, Movement IV (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Eight Pieces, Intermezzo, Bb Major, Op. 76/4, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Eight Pieces, Intermezzo, A minor, Op. 76/7, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Six Songs, "Feldeinsamkeit", Op. 86/2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fourth Symphony, Op. 98, Movement I (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Seven Fantasias, Intermezzo, E Major, Op. 116/4, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Includes analysis by Seth Monahan.
    - Seven Fantasias, Intermezzo, E Minor, Op. 116/5, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Four Pieces, Intermezzo, Op. 199/1, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Britten, Benjamin (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Serenade, Elegy, Op. 31/4
  - Bruckner, Anton, 1979; 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Seventh Symphony, Adagio, Movement II. Includes analyses by L. Zbikowski and Paul Wilson.
  - Carter, Elliot, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Analyses of "Eight Etudes and a Fantasy for Woodwind Quartet", No. 5 and 6.
  - Chopin, Fredéric (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Nocturne, Op. 9/2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Etude, Op. 10/3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mazurka,Op. 17/4, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Includes analysis by Beach.
    - Prelude, Op. 28/3, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prelude, Op 28/4 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prelude, Op. 28/9 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prelude, Op. 28/13 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prelude, Op. 28/14 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prelude, Op. 28/17, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prelude, Op. 28/21, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mazurka, Op. 33/1, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ballade, Op. 47/3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Nocturne, Op. 48/1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mazurka, Op. 59/1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mazurka, Op. 59/2, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Includes letter and anlysis from Ernst Oster.
    - Mazurka, Op. 68/4, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dallapiccola, Luigi (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Analysis of "Quaderno Musicale di Annalibera".
  - Debussy, Claude (Box 3)
    - Ariettes oubliées, L60, "C'est l'extase" (no. 1), "L'ombre des arbres" (No. 3) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cinq poèmes de Charles Baudelaire, L64, "Harmonie du soir" (No. 2), "Recueillement" (No. 4) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - String Quartet, G minor, L85, Op. 10, Movement I and III, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Prelude to Afternoon of a Faun, L86, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Chansons de Bilitis, L90, "La chevelure" (No. 2), "Le tombeau des Naiades" (No. 3), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Nocturnes, L91, "Nuages" (No. 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fêtes galantes, Set 2, L104, "Les ingénus" (No. 1) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - L'isle joyeuse, L106 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - La Mer, L109, Movement III (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Images I, L110 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Images II, L111 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Preludes, Book 1, L117, Various (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Includes "Danseuses de Delphes" (No. 1), "Voiles" (No. 2), "Les sons et les parfums tournent dans l'air du soir" (No. 4), "Ce qu'a vu le Vent d'Ouest' (No. 7).
    - Preludes, Book 2, No. 2, L123 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Preludes, Book 2, No. 7, L123 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Preludes, Book 2, No. 8, L123, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1, L135 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Études, Livre I, L136 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Études, Livre II, L136 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Harmonic Fields - General (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Includes "A sightseer's guide to Debussy's harmony".
  - Handel, George Frideric (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Analyses of Suite V, Air (HWV430), Suite VIII, Courante (HWV433), Suite X, Menuetto, (HWV436), Suite XII, Courante (HWV437)
  - Haydn, Joseph (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Creation, Prelude, "Die Vorstellung des Chaos" (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Contains transcriptions of and notes about three drafts of the score, notes not written by AF.
    - Sonatas (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Includes analyses of Sonatas XVI/21-Andante, XVI/22-Andante, XVI/28-Menuet, XVI/44. Letter from Ernst Oster regarding XVI/44. Analysis of XVI/28-Menuet by Jonathan Bernard.
    - String Quartet, Op. 76/5, Movement II, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Symphony No. 45, No. 2, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ives, Charles (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 34 Songs, No. 24 "Soliloquy" (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 114 Songs (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Contains general notes on 114 Songs, and analytical material about several, including No. 15, 23, 39.
    - Piano Sonata No.2 (Concord), Movement IV (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Unanswered Question (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Violin Sonata No. 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Liszt, Franz (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Années de pèlerinage (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Includes analyses of "Vallée d'Obermann" (Première année: Suisse) and "Sposalizio" (Deuxième année: Italie).
    - Piano Sonata, B Minor (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mahler, Gustav (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Das Lied von der Erder, No. 3, "Von der Jugend" (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Symphony 5, Adagietto (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Symphony No. 9, Movement IV (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Mendelssohn, Felix, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Analysis of Variations Serieuses, Op. 54.
  - Messiaen, Oliver (Box 4)
    - Preludes for Piano, "La colombe" (No. I), "Instants défunts" (No. IV), "Plainte calme" (No. VII) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Quatuor pour la fin du temps, No. 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Vingt Regards sur l'enfant-Jésus, X (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Livre D'Orgue, Movements I - VII (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang (Box 4)
    - Piano Sonatas (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Analyses of piano sontatas No. 2 (K280), 4 (K282), 10 (K330), 11 (K331 - includes letter from Ernst Oster), 12 (K332), 13 (K333), 15 (K533), 16 (K545), 17 (K570).
    - Piano Sonata Themes (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Minuet in D, K355 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - String Quartets (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Analyses for String Quartets No. 15/3 (K421), 16/2 (K428),18 (K464), 19/1 and 19/2 (K465)
    - Piano Concerto No. 23 in A major, K488 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Rondo No. 3 in A minor, K511 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Serenade No. 13 in G major, "Eine kleine Nachtmusik", K525, II - Romance (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Don Giovanni, K527, Aria "Dalla sua pace" (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Adagio for Piano in B minor, K540 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mussorgsky, Modest (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Analytical materials for Boris Gudunov, the "Clock" Scene.
  - Prokofiev, Sergei (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Analyses of Visions fugitives, No. 2 and 11. Analysis of Romeo and Juliet, "The Balcony Scene".
  - Ravel, Maurice (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Analyses of Chansons madécasses, No. 2; Miroirs for piano, "Oiseaux tristes"; Trois poèmes de Stéphane Mallarmé, No. 3.
  - Schoenberg, Arnold (Box 4)
    - 4 Lieder für eine Singstimme und Klavier, Op. 2/1-4 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 6 Lieder für eine mittlere Singstimme und Klavier, Op. 3/1-6 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 8 Lieder für eine Singstimme und Klavier, Op. 6/1-3, 6-8, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 1. Streichquartett (d-Moll), Op. 7 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 6 Orchesterlieder, Op. 8/1-6, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Kammersymphonie für 15 Soloinstrumente, Op. 9 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Includes copy of Berg's analysis.
    - 2. Streichquartett (fis-Moll) für Quartett und eine Sopranstimme, Op. 10, Movement III, IV, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 3 Klavierstücke, Op. 11/1-3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2 Lieder für Gesang und Klavier, Op. 12 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2 Balladen für Gesang und Klavier, Op. 12/1-2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2 Lieder für Gesang und Klavier, Op. 14/1-2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 15 Gedichte aus "Das Buch der hängenden Gärten" Op. 15/1-13, 15 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 5 Orchesterstücke in der Originalfassung für großes Orchester, Op. 16/1-5 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Erwartung – Monodram in einem Akt, Op. 17 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Die glückliche Hand – Drama mit Musik, Op. 18 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 6 kleine Klavierstücke, Op. 19/1-3, 5-6 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Herzgewächse – für hohen Sopran, Celesta, Harmonium und Harfe, Op. 20 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Pierrot lunaire, Op. 21, Part I (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Pierrot lunaire, Op. 21, Part II (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Analyses of Part II, No. 8-11, 12-14.
    - Pierrot lunaire, Op. 21, Part III (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Analyses of Part III, No. 16-17, 19, 21.
    - 4 Lieder für Gesang und Orchester, Op. 22/1-2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 5 Klavierstücke, Op. 23/1-5 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Serenade, Op. 24/1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Serenade, Op. 24/3-4, 6 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Suite für Klavier, Op. 25/1-3 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 4 Stücke für gemischten Chor, Op. 27/1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 3 Satiren für gemischten Chor, Op. 28/2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 3. Streichquartett, Op. 30/1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Variationen für Orchester, Op. 31 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 6 Stücke für Männerchor, Op. 35/1-4, 6 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 4. Streichquartett, Op. 37, Movement I and III (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Kammersymphonie Nr. 2 für kleines Orchester, Op. 38 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - A Survivor from Warsaw, Op. 46 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Phantasy for Violin with Piano Accompaniment, Op. 47 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 3 Lieder für tiefe Stimme (und Klavier), Op. 48/2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Am Strande, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Die Jakobsleiter (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Gedenken (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Gurrelieder (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Schoenberg's Twelve Tone Rows (Box 6, Folder 4)
      List of twelve tone rows for most of Schoenberg's compositions. Extracted from Maegaard, "Schönberg Zwölftonreihen", 1976.
  - Schubert, Franz (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet No. 4, D.46, Andante (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet No. 9, D.173, Menuetto, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Du bist die Ruh, D.776, Op. 59/3 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Moments musicaux, D.780, Op. 94/6, Allegretto, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Die schöne Müllerin, D. 795, Op. 25/2, "Wohin?", Op. 25/11 "Mein!", 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Ständchen, D.889 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Impromptu, D.935, Op. 142/2, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Schwanengesang, D.957/3, Frühlingssehnsucht, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Schwanengesang, D.957/9, Ihr Bild, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No.19, D.958, Adagio (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Winterreise, D.911/3, Op. 89/3, Gefror'ne Thränen (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Winterreise, D.911/6, Op. 89/6, Wasserflut, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Winterreise, D.911/12, Op. 89/12, Einsamkeit, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Winterreise, D.911/20, Op. 89/20, Der Wegweiser, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Various German Waltzes and Dances (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Analyses of D.365/2,8,11 (Op. 9); D.783/5,10 (Op. 33); D.779/12,19 (Op. 50); D.146/10,17 (Op. 127); D.790/3 (Op. 171).
    - Die schöne Müllerin, D. 795, Op. 25/11, "Mein!" (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Schumann, Robert (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Liederkreis, Op. 24/6, "Warte, warte, wilder Schiffmann" (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dichterliebe, Op. 48/4, "Wenn ich in deine Augen seh" (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dichterliebe, Op. 48/13, "Ich hab' im Traum geweinet" (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Includes letter from Erst Oster, 1966.
  - Scriabin, Alexander (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Piano Sonata No.4, Op. 30, Movement I, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Piano Sonata No.6, Op. 62, Movement I (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 2 Poèmes, Op. 63/2, "Etrangeté" (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 2 Preludes, Op. 67/1, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 5 Preludes, Op. 74/1,3,4 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Stockhausen, Karlheinz (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Analyses of Klavierstück II, Movement 2 and 3.
  - Strauss, Richard (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letzte Lieder, No. 1, "Frühling" (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Tod und Verklärung, Op. 24, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stravinsky, Igor (Box 7)
    - The Firebird, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Analyses of "Arrivée de Kachtcheï l'Immortel", "Dialogue de Kachtcheï avec Ivan Tsarévitch", and "Intercession des princesses". Analyses of "L'Oiseau de feu", various sections.
    - 2 Poems by Paul Verlaine, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 2 Poems by Konstantin Balmont, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - King of the Stars (Zvezdoliki), 1911 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Le roi des étoiles, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 3 Japanese Lyrics, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Le rossignol, 1908-1914 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The Rite of Spring, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Introduction to Part I, Introduction to Part II (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Ritual of the Rival Tribes (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Dance of the Earth (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Mystic Circles of the Adolescents (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Glorification of the Chosen One (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Evocation and Ritual Action (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Danse sacrale, 1943 version (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Rite of Spring Sketchbook: Comments, Locations and maps of pages (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Rite of Spring manuscript (Box 7, Folder 5)
        Photos of pages of manuscript sold 1982.
    - Three Pieces for String Quartet, 1914, No. 2 and 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Les Noces, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - L'histoire du soldat, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Symphonies of Wind Instruments, 1920/1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Petrouchka, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Octet, Tema con Variazioni, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Oedipus Rex, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Symphony of Psalms, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Septet, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - In Memoriam Dylan Thomas, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Agon, Bransle Gay and Bransle Double (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Double Canon, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - A Sermon, a Narrative, and a Prayer, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Sacher Stiftung - Various Stravinsky works (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Undated; appear to be notes from lecture(s) given by Sacher Stiftung on various Stranvinsky works: 3 Pieces for String Quartet, Histoire du Soldat, Symphonies of Winds, Sonate, Serenade en la, Symphony of Psalms, Mass, Canticum sacrum, Agon.
  - Wagner, Richard (Box 8)
    - Tristan und Isolde, Prelude (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Tristan und Isolde, Act III, Horn Solo (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Webern, Anton (Box 8)
    - 5 Lieder aus Der siebente Ring für Stimme und Klavier, Op. 3/1, 3, 4, 5 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 5 Lieder nach Gedichten von Stefan George für Stimme und Klavier, Op. 4/4 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 6 Stücke für Orchester, Op. 6/1-6 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 4 Stücke für Violine und Klavier, Op. 7 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 2 Lieder nach Gedichten von Ranier Maria Rilke, Op. 8 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bagatellen für Streichquartett, Op. 9 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 5 Stücke für Orchester, Op. 10/1, 2, 3, 5 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 5 Stücke für Orchester, Op. 10/1, 2, 3, 5 [Oversize] (Box 8A)
      Analytical sketches of Opus 10/4 and 10/5.
    - 3 kleine Stücke für Violoncello und Klavier, Op. 11 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 4 Lieder für Stimme und Klavier, Op. 12 (Box 8, Folder 4)